여보세요?
Allo?
- 안녕. 톰.
- 안녕하세요.
- Hi, Tom.
- Good morning.
안녕하세요. 자꾸에.
Hello, Jaques.
세상에나. 톰!
Oh, my God. Tom!
숨어요. 어서 숨어요!
Okay, take cover, take cover now!
7층으로 가는 출입 통로가 몇 개나 되나요?
How many ways in and
out of the seventh floor?
- 무슨 일인데요?
- 누가 7층에서
- What is going on?
- Someone is shooting
총을 쏘고 있어요! 몇 개나 되나요?
from the seventh floor! How many ways?
그냥 내부 계단하고 엘리베이터 그거 뿐이에요.
Just the stairwell and the lift, that's it.
엘리베이터 중지시키세요. 경찰에 전화하구요.
Kill the lift. Call the police,
현 위치에서 총기 난사 사건이 발생했다고 말하세요.
tell them there is a mass
shooting at this address.
그냥 기다리면 안될까...?
Shouldn't you just wait for...
경찰이다! 무장중이다!
Police! I am armed!
여기는 견습 경찰관 아네트...
This is Probationary Officer Annette...
신참들이 저지르는 가장 큰 실수가 뭔줄 알아?
Know the biggest mistake a rookie makes?
총을 뽑아들고서
When they draw their weapon,
똑바로 앞만 쳐다보다는거지.
they only see what's
directly in front of it.
그걸 터널시라고 하지.
It's called tunnel vision.
앤-마리 어머니께서 언제 오시나요?
What time is her mother coming?
빠리에서 오후 5시에 도착한다고 그러시더군.
She said she would be on
the 5:00 p.m. from Paris.
얼마나 힘든 여정이실지 상상해보세요.
Imagine how hard that trip will be.
아마도 마지막 여정보다는 쉬우시겠지.
Probably easier than her last trip.
그게 마지막 여정은 최소한 희망이라도 있지.
Well, on the last trip
at least there was hope.
오늘 아침 헤이그에는 그건 뭐지?
What is it about morning in The Hague, huh?
그림의 밝은 색깔이 베르메르 작품처럼 보이던데.
The light looks like a Vermeer.
베르메르도 아신다?
Oh, you know Vermeer?
내가 놀래켜줬나요. 루이?
Does that surprise you, Louis?
뭐 그렇다는거죠.
Kind of.
그 박스에는 뭐가 있나?
What's in the box?
앤-마리 물건들요.
Anne-Marie's things.
그것도 까먹지말고.
Don't forget that.
실은 내 생각에... 자네가 원할거 같군.
Actually, I thought... you might want it.
그래요. 그럼 좋겠군요. 고마워요.
Yeah, I'd like that. Thanks.
- 칼튼. 잠깐 시간있나?
- 예.
- Carlton, do you have a minute?
- Yeah.
히크먼이 앤-마리 명패를 원한다고?
Hickman wants her nameplate?
놀라운일은 아닌데.
It's not so surprising.
안녕들 하신가.
Good morning, all.
안녕. 공식적으로 합류하게 되서 기뻐.
Hey, glad to officially have you on board.
- 합류하게 되서 나도 기뻐.
- 환영해.
- Glad to be on board.
- Welcome.
고마워. 에바. 고마워. 밀.
Grazie, Eva. Grazie mille.
이탈이어도 해?
You speak Italian?
네델란드어, 독일어, 영어.
And Dutch, and German, and English.
게일어는?
What about Irish?
미안. 게일어는 아무도 모르잖아. Sorry, nobody understands Irish.
Sorry, nobody understands Irish.
하느님 아버지네.
Amen.
여기가 내 자리야?
Is this me?
어... 그래. 맞아. 이 자리.
Uh... yeah. Yeah, it's yours.
어제 아침 빠리에서 발생한 저격건인가요?
This the sniper in Paris yesterday morning?
다섯명 사망. 경찰관 두 명 포함해서
Five dead, including two police officers,
훈련 담당 경관과 젊은 신참이 아침을 먹을려고 할 때 발생했지.
a young rookie with her training
officer having breakfast.
안 좋은 시간에 안 좋은 장소에 있게 됐다?
Wrong place, wrong time?
그렇게 보이네.
Appears that way.
- 나한테 보여주고 싶은게 이거 였나요?
- 아니.
- This what you wanted to show me?
- No.
레베카에 관한 거야.
It's about Rebecca.
우리 담당 검사가 될거네.
She's going to be our prosecutor.
잘한다고 들었는데.
I hear she was good.
아주 잘한다고.
Very good.
- 준비는 되었다고 하던가요?
- 그렇다고 생각하네.
- Is she ready?
- Yes. I think so.
- 팀장님?
- 어?
- Major?
- Yeah?
죄송한데요. 돈이 빠리에선 온 모로 형사와 같이 오셨는데요?
I'm sorry. Dorn is here with
Moreau, the Paris detective?
- 가겠네.
- 알겠습니다.
- I'm coming.
- Okay.
도움이 필요하시면 말씀하십시오.
If I can be of help, you let me know.
정말 고맙네.
Thank you very much.
여기있군. 루이. 히크먼. 모로 형사 알아보시겠군?
Here. Louis, Hickman, you recognize Moreau?
빠리에서 발생한 끔직한 저격건으로 오셨다네.
He's just come from that
horrific sniper shooting in Paris
저격한 범인을 추적하는데 도움을 요청하러 말이지.
to request our help tracking the shooter.
저격자가 남겨놓은 메모가 있어.
There was a note left by the shooter.
원본은 증거물 검사를 위해 있고
The original is being tested for evidence,
내... 내가 사진 찍은 걸 가져왔어요.
but I... I brought you a photocopy.
프롤레타리아들은 bellyfeel blackwhite를 거부할 것이다.
"The proles will refuse
to bellyfeel blackwhite.
목요일까지 백만 유로를 내놔라
One hundred million Euro by Thursday,
그렇지 않으면 유럽 어딘가에서 다섯명 이상이 죽을것이다.
or five more will die somewhere in Europe.
Subtitles by 나를 멈출순 없다. W.S.
You cannot stop me. W.S."
목요일까지? 잠깐 봐도?
By Thursday? May I?
내일이잖아.
Tomorrow.
"Bellyfeel blackwhite?" 도대체 무슨 말이야?
"Bellyfeel blackwhite?"
What the hell does that mean?
그건 신(조)어인데,
It's Newspeak,
조지 오웰이 1984란 소설에서 만들어낸 말이지.
which is, of course, the language
that George Orwell created for 1984.
무슨 말인가요?
What does it mean?
아. 그게 구어에서는 대충 이런 의미지...
Ah, well, in Oldspeak,
it... roughly it means,
사람들 눈을 속일 수 없다.
"You can't pull the wool
over the peoples' eyes."
특히 이번 사건에서 난...
In this particular instance, I...
내 생각엔 본능적으로 사람들은
I think it means that instinctively
검은 것을 흰색이다라고 하는 개념을 거부할것이라는 의미라고 보네.
people will reject the
notion that black is white.
검은 것이 흰색이라고요?
Black is white?
그 책의 주요 전제 중 하나지.
It's one of the central
premises of the book.
권위적인 독재 정권은 시민들이
The authoritarian government insists that
본질적으로 허구의 것들은 무조건적으로 믿도록 강요한단 말이지.
citizens unquestioningly believe
things that are inherently untrue.
검은 것은 흰색이다. 이런 것처럼
Such as black is white.
그자가 W.S.라고 싸인을 남겼네요.
He signs it "W.S."
그게 소설 속 주인공 이름이 윈스턴 스미스이라서 그런거지.
Well, because the main character
in the novel is Winston Smith.
윈스턴 스미스가 관료가 아니었잖아요? 정부 직원인가?
Wasn't Winston Smith a
bureaucrat? A functionary?
그가 폭력적이었는지 전혀 기억이 안나네요.
I don't remember him being violent at all.
아니 그는 폭력적이지가 않았지. 확실히 그 누구도 죽이지 않았고 말이야.
No, he wasn't. And certainly,
he didn't kill anyone,
그리고 하고 많은 사람들 중에
and of all people, he would not
그는 무작위 다중을 타겟으로 하는 그런 일에는 참여하지 않겠지.
be participant in the
multiple targeting at random.
그럼 그자는 그냥 우리는 떨쳐버릴려고 그짓을 했을지도 모르겠네요.
Well, then, maybe he's just
doing this to throw us off.
이런 류의 살인자는 보통 아무 이유없이 이런 일을 벌이지 않지.
A killer like this usually
doesn't do anything without reason.
솔직히 그자는 어느 누가 자기한테 그 돈을 주겠어 하고 믿고 있지 않겠지.
He can't honestly believe anyone's
going to give him that money.
모로 형사. 그자가 떠난 이후로 누구와 연락을 취한적 있나요?
Moreau, has he been in contact
with anyone since he left that note?
아니. 아무도 없어요.
No. No one.
그럼 그자는 그 돈을 바라고 있지 않는거네.
Well, then, he's not
expecting to get any money.
그자는 자기 본래 목적이 뭔지
He's using this as a ruse
우리가 알아채지 못하게할려고 이런 책략을 쓰고 있는거지.
to keep us from understanding
what his true goal is.
소설 1984를 이해시키는것부터 시작해서 말이죠.
Which starts with understanding 1984.
이 광장에는 틀림없이 다섯명 이상의 사람들이 있었을텐데
The square, it must have
more than five people in it.
왜 그만 쐈을까요?
Why'd he stop shooting?
처음엔 사람들이 도망쳐서 그랬을거라고 생각했어요.
Initially, we thought
people must have run away.
근데 딱 한발의 총성만 있었다고 하더군요.
But there was only one shot heard.
- 총 한방에 다섯 사람을 죽였다고요?
- 아니. 그게 아니고.
- One shot that killed five people?
- No, no,
단지 딱 한발의 총성 소리만 들렸다고 하더라구요.
but there was only one shot heard.
그리고는 여성 경찰관이 광장을 가로질러 건물안으로 들어갔구요.
And then the female officer ran
across the square into the building.
- 아주 큰 위험을 떠안았던거네.
- 그자가 그 여경을 쐈나요?
- She took a grand risk.
- Is that when he shot her?
그녀는 총을 맞지 않았어요.
She wasn't shot.
사격하는 쪽에서 대치하고 있었죠.
There was a confrontation
at the site of the shooting.
그자가 그 여경을 7층 창문밖으로 밀어버려서 사망했죠.
He pushed her out the window,
seven floors to her death.
그러면 이 사건을 맡으실건가요?
So you're taking the case?
그래요. 근데 질문이 있는데
Yes. But I have a question.
당신 상관이 당신이 여기있는걸 알고 있나요?
Does your boss know you're here?
모로 형사. 사건 현장으로 가게.
Moreau, go to the scene.
내가 법원에가서 재가를 받도록 하지.
I'll get it authorized in the Court.
그게 라보가 제기할만한 어떠한 반대에 대응할만큼 충분하겠지.
That should be enough to handle any
objections that Laveaux might have.
안에 들어가면 더 편하게 느껴질거네.
You'll be more comfortable inside.
학교에 처음으로 등교하는 어린애같은 기분이 드네요.
I feel like a child on
her first day at school.
학교에 재등교하는 첫날이지.
First day back to school,
그리고 자네가 아주 뛰어나게 잘 해낼 수 있는 학교지. 레베가.
and it's a school in
which you excel, Rebecca.
들어갑니다.
Here goes.
자네가 그만둘 때만큼 우아한건 아니지.
Well, it's not as elegant
as the one you left.
왜요. 아주 좋은데요.
Please. It's absolutely fine.
나랑 같이 가세. 레베카.
Come with me, Rebecca.
빠리에서 발생한 저격 사건을
I have to get authorization from the Court
추적할 수 있도록 법원에서 재가 받아야 하거든.
allowing our team to
track the sniper in Paris.
자네가 새로 시작하기에 안성맞춤이지.
It's a good place for you to start.
내 생각엔 말이네. 자네가
I think that you should be a part
이 사건의 맨 처음부터 동참했으면 하네.
of this case right from the very beginning.
저기... 잠시만 몸단장 좀 하고 싶은데요.
Can I... I just need
a moment to freshen up.
난 홀에 내려가 있겠네.
I'll just be down the hall.
아 정말 내가 여기서 뭘하고 있는거지?
Oh, God, what am I doing here?
Okay.
난 할 수 있어. I can do this.
I can do this.
칼?
Carl?
뭔가 빠졌어요.
I'm missing something,
바로 내 앞에 뭔가가요.
something right in front of me.
그럼 계속 하게.
Well, stay on it.
우리한테 시간이 그리 많지 않은데 하물며 어떻게 진행하겠어.
We don't have much time,
and even less to go on.
희생자 3명 파일밖에 없는데요?
There are only three victim files?
예. 환경 미화원, 자전거 이용자, 언어를 배우려는 외국인 가사 도우미.
Yes, a sanitation worker,
a bicyclist, and an au pair,
아무런 연관성이 없음이 판명되었어요.
but we found no connection.
그런데 희생자는 다섯명이잖아요.
Yeah, but there were five victims.
경찰관들은 어떤가요?
What about the officers?
경찰관들을 조사하고 싶다고요?
You want to investigate them?
그 경찰관들이 누구인지 알아야겠죠.
We need to know who they were.
뭔가요?
What is it?
두 명의 빠리 경찰관이 살해당한 후라
Two Parisian officers were murdered,
우리 형사들한테는 외부 요원들이
so our detectives are not going to be happy
자기들 사건에 끼어드는 걸 반가워하지 않을거 같아서요.
about an outside agency
intruding on their case.
사건과 연관시켜 이용할 유일한 이유는
The only reason for use to be involved
다른 나라에서 총격 사건이 발생할 수도 있어서죠.
would be another shooting
in a different country.
그렇지. 그거야.
That's it, that's it.
이게 날 괴롭히는 거였어.
That's what's bugging me.
다섯명 이상의 유럽 어딘가에서 죽을것이다.
"Five more will die somewhere in Europe."
그자가 '다섯명 이상이 죽을것이다'라고 말했다면
If he had said, "Five more will die,"
그 가정은 그자가 빠리에서 하겠다는 말이 되겠죠.
the assumption would be that he meant Paris
그러면 우리는 그 사건을 맡을 수 없는거고.
and we could not be on the case.
이 메모는 우리가 연관되어 있다는 걸
This note has the exact right phrasing
확신시켜주기 위해 정확히 딱 맞는 말을 써놨어요.
to ensure that we are involved.
계획되었다는 생각이군.
You think it was planned.
잘은 모르겠지만...
I don't know, but...
우연의 일치 개념 때문에 힘든 시간을 보냈어요.
I got a hard time with
the concept of coincidence.
새팀이 국경을 넘어서 벌어지는 범죄에 맞붙다.
여성 탈의실에서 오히려 더 환영받았을거라는 기분이 드네.
I've felt more welcome in
the ladies changing room.
정말로? 난 환영이라는 걸 받아본적이 없는 사람이라서.
Really? I've never been welcome in one.
세바스찬. 저기 무슨 증거가 있는지 확인해보고.
Sebastian, check up there
if there is any evidence.
아라벨라. 나하고 같이 가세. 우리는 증인들과 이야기 해보겠네.
Arabela, come with me.
We'll talk to the witnesses.
타미하고 에바는 전술적인 부분을 검토하도록
Tommy and Eva, look at the tactical.
- 그자가 어떻게 했는지 알고 싶은신건가요?
- 주로 저기서부터 했어.
- Do you want to know how he did it?
- Mostly why he did it from there.
라보 서장님
Commissaire Laveaux.
이 사건 현장은 폐쇄되었소.
This scene is closed.
ICC에서 내려온 권한이 있어요.
I have an authorization from the ICC.
이건 ICC와 아무런 관련이 없어요.
This has nothing to do with the ICC.
두 명의 빠리 경찰관이 살해당했어요.
Two Parisian officers were killed.
- 당신이 그냥 들어올 수 없어...
- 맞습니다. 맞아요.
- You can't just come in here...
- You're right. You're right.
맞구요. 맞아요. 맞아.
You're right. You're right. You're right.
서장님 부하 동료들을 죽인 자가
The man who killed your comrades
유럽 어디간에서 똑같은 짓을 벌이겠다고 협박하는 메모를 남겨놨잖아요.
left a note threatening to do
the same somewhere in Europe.
우리는 단지 이 사건이
We will participate only
우리를 프랑스에서 외부 어느 나라로 데려다 줄 수 있는지 그것에만 관여할겁니다.
if the case takes us outside
of France to another country.
그때까지 우리가 도움을 제공하고 싶군요.
Until then, we want to provide assistance.
두 명의 경찰관을 잃으신거에 공감합니다.
You lost two officers
and I know what you feel,
당신에게 오는 압박들이 얼마나 심할지. 그냥 돕고 싶어서 그래요.
the pressure you are
under. I just want to help.
약속할게요.
I give you my word.
이 사람들에게 사건 현장을 보여드려.
Show them the scene.
고맙습니다.
Thank you.
오늘 빠리에서 저격수가 발포한 곳은
... today in Paris where
a sniper opened fire
공공 광장으로 ... 대학교에서
in a public square not far from...
... 멀리 떨어져 있지 않은
... National University...
위스키 드려요?
Whiskey?
오늘 오전 9시에 ...
... at 9:00 a.m. this morning,
- 두 명의 프랑스 경찰...
- 더블로.
- two French police officers...
- Double.
다른 세명의 시민들과 함께 살해당했습니다.
were killed, along with
three other civilians.
희생자들은 사건 현장에서 바로 사망했습니다.
The victims were pronounced
dead at the scene.
검시관은 결론지었습니다.
The medical examiner has determined...
...한 발의 총알이 머리를 관통하는 총살형 같은 방식으로 공격을 받았습니다.
... were struck, execution-style,
with a single bullet to the head.
경찰은 희생자의 신원을 밝히지 않았습니다.
Police have not released the
identities of the victims,
- 통지가 될 때까지...
- 한 잔 더.
- pending notification...
- Another.
가까운 친척에게
of next of kin.
법원에서 발급받은 권한서를 찢어버린다?
Tearing up our authorization
form from the Court?
내가 그랬던가 안그랬던가?
Did I, or did I not?
Ah...
시거. 이건은 자네한테 가르쳐줄게 많이 있네.
Seeger, this one has much to teach you.
내 생각엔 여러분들 다 한테도 그럴거 같은데요.
I think you all do.
길거리 커피 장사 사장과 이야기하고 싶다면 그 사람은 준비됐어요.
The coffee cart owner is ready
if you'd like to talk to him.
예.
Yeah.
최적의 장소는 아닌데
It's not optimal.
광장 반대편쪽이라면 모를까.
The other side of the square would be.
아침 이 시각이면 태양이 그자 뒤에 있었겠지.
The sun would be behind him
at this time in the morning.
그자가 이런 경험이 없을지도 모르겠네?
Maybe he isn't that experienced?
이 사정거리에서 움직이는 타겟을 못맞추면 그건 아마추어지.
Nobody who can hit a moving target
from this range is an amateur,
특히 태양쪽으로 쏜다면 말이지.
especially shooting into the sun.
내 추측으로는 군사 훈련을 받은거 같은데
My guess would be military training.
그것도 많이
A lot of it.
이 건물을 이용한 또 다른 이유가 있어.
There are other reasons
to use this building,
태양이 영향이 있다는 걸 불구하고도 말이야.
though, despite the sun.
예를 들자면 이 층은 공사중이지.
For instance, this floor
being under construction.
히크먼이 말한것처럼 이건 아마도 우연의 일치가 아닐거야.
Like Hickman says, that's
probably no coincidence.
스캔할 준비가 됐어.
I'm ready for some scans.
자끄 르미에르. L E M I E...
Jaques Lemi?e. L-E-M-I...
다른 경찰관들이 당신 이름을 알고 있어요.
The other officers have your name.
우리는 그냥 당신이 뭘 기억하고 있는지 알고 싶은거 뿐이에요.
We just want to know what you remember.
기억하는 거요? 다 기억하고 있어요. 난...
Remember? I remember all of it. I...
절대 잊지 못할거에요.
I will never forget.
어떻게 이런걸 잊어버리겠어요?
How can I ever forget something like this?
내 말은 당신이 TV을 보다가 하지만 생각못하겠죠...
I mean, you watch television, but
you don't think it will ever...
당신말고 다른 사람들. 하지만...
Not to you. Other people, but
- 당신 말고...
- 자끄...
- not you...
- Jaques...
숨 좀 돌리세요.
breathe.
자 이제 앉아서 물 한모금 하시고 진정하세요.
Now, sit and take a
sip of water, and relax.
이거 보게.
Look at that.
뭔데?
What?
창틀에, 그자가 쐈던데?
The window frame, the one he fired from?
골고루 거의 완벽하게 가스로 둘러쌓여있네.
There's a smooth, almost
perfect covering of gases
발사된 탄환 잔여물이랑 같이
and gunshot residue.
틀 어느 부분에?
On what part of the frame?
틀 다
All of it.
위, 아래, 양 옆에 다
Top, bottom, sides.
심지어 사방으로 다 퍼져있어.
It's an even dispersement
in all directions.
그래서 아무도 총소리를 못 들었던거네.
That's why no one heard the shots.
난 그냥 장 아침을 가지고 나왔었죠.
I had just brought out Jean's breakfast.
장?
Jean?
예. 이 지역을 도보로 순찰하는 지역 경찰관이에요.
Yes, the local officer who walks this area.
여경하고 같이 있던 경찰관?
The one with the female officer?
예. 그래요. 아네뜨. 장 수습 경찰관이죠. 그녀는...
Yeah. Yeah, Anette, his trainee. She was...
그녀한테 일어난 일은...
What happened to her was...
- 자끄. 집중하세요.
- 알았어요.
- Jaques, stay focused.
- Okay.
경찰관이 도착해서 주문했다?
The officer arrived and ordered coffee?
아니 그게 아니고 먼저 주문한걸 준비해놓고 있었어요.
No. No, I prepared his order first.
먼저? 그 경찰관이 도착하기 전에?
First? Before he arrived?
예. 장은 칼같이 아침 9시면 이곳에 와요. 그는 아주 체계적인 사람이죠.
Yes, Jean is here every morning,
9:00 sharp. He is very methodical.
그랬죠. 체계적인 사람이었죠.
Was. He was methodical.
그 다음에는 무슨 일이 생긴거죠?
What happened next?
다른 주문을 받고 있던 중에 한 번의 총성이 났죠.
Um, I was taking another
order, and there was a shot.
한 번의 총성.
A shot.
예. 한 번의 총성. 마치 쿵하는 소리...
Yes, one shot, like... like a crack.
돌아서니까 이 빌딩에서 나왔다는 걸 볼 수 있었어요.
I turned, and could see
it came from this building.
연기를 봤어요.
I saw the smoke,
그자가 라이플을 물리는 걸 보았죠.
saw the rifle being pulled back in,
그리고 아네뜨가 소리치는 걸 듣고나서 장을 보았죠.
and I heard Anette make a
sound, and then I saw Jean.
그는...
He was...
총을 맞았어요.
he had been hit.
그 한 방이 그 경찰관을 맞췄다?
That one shot hit the officer?
그래요.
Yeah.
그러고 나서 아네뜨가 건물쪽으로 뛰어갔어요.
And then Anette ran
off toward the building,
그제서야 난...
and it was only after that I...
사람들이 바닥에 엎어져 있는걸 알아챘죠. 다른 사람들도 총을 맞았던 거죠.
I noticed other people on the ground,
other people that had been shot.
아네뜨가 뛰어갈 때 다른 사람들은 이미 총을 맞았다는 말인가요?
After the officer ran off,
the others were already shot?
예.
Yes.
- 확실하다는 거군요.
- 예. 확신해요.
- You're sure.
- Yeah, I'm sure.
"Bellyfeel blackwhite... "
"Bellyfeel blackwhite."
"Bellyfeel... "
우리 팀이 이 메모를 수십번 검토했죠.
My team has gone over this note many times.
말이 정말 안되게 보이죠?
It doesn't seem to make much sense, huh?
우리 또한 1984 책을 검토하고 있어요.
We're going through 1984 as well.
법의학자가 원본을 가지고 돌아왔죠. 그 메모는 철저히 깨끗하답디다.
Forensics came back on the original.
The note is completely clean.
지문도 없고 DNA도 없고
No prints, no DNA.
손으로 쓴 메모에 지문이나 DNA가 남질 않는다는건 쉽지 않은데
Can't be easy to handwrite a
note and leave no prints or DNA.
이하 동문
Same thing I thought.
그자는 네발의 총을 쐈어요.
Four shots in the time he had
그가 총을 쐈던 곳은 아주 놀라울 정도로 최적의 장소에요.
and from where he shot is remarkably good.
주변 법의학자도 역시 그자의 방식을 알고 있어.
Knows his way around forensics, too.
메모에 지문도 없고 DNA도 없어.
No prints or DNA on the note.
우리가 현재 그 경찰관을 검토하고 있나요?
Are we looking at a cop?
물론 그런쪽으로 검토를 시작해야지.
Sure starting to look that way.
그리고 또 왜 아무도 총소리를 듣지 못했는지 알아냈어요.
And we also know why
no one heard any shots.
예. 스캔젠이 발사된 탄환 잔여물과 가스 입자를 집어 냈어요.
Yeah. The ScanGen picked up
gunshot residue and gas particles
창틀에 넓게, 넓게 퍼지는 패턴으로
on the window frame in a wide,
in a wide diffuse pattern.
골고루 퍼지는 건 소음기의 가스를 배출하는 방식이죠.
Evenly spread, the way a
suppressor would dispense the gases.
- 하지만 사람들이 한 방의 총성을 들었잖아요.
- 그래. 마지막 꺼.
- But they did hear one shot.
- Yes, the last one.
그 한 발은 선배 경찰을 죽이고 신참을 끌어들이기용이었던거지.
The one that killed the
older cop and drew the rookie.
그 경찰관들은 안 좋은 시간에 안 좋은 장소에 있던게 아니었던거지.
Those officers weren't
wrong place, wrong time.
그 경찰관들이 타겟이었지.
They were the targets.
그 경찰관들이 타겟이었다고요?
The officers were the target?
사람들이 들었던 딱 한 발만이
The only shot that anybody heard
선배 경찰관을 죽였던 총알이지요.
was the one that killed
the older police officer.
목격자 말에 의하면 그 경찰관이 총을 맞았을 때
The witness said when
the officer was shot...
다른 사람들은 이미 바닥에 널부러져 있었지.
The others were already on the ground.
소리가 들렸던 총성이 마지막 거였던 거지.
The audible shot was the last one.
그자는 소음기를 사용하고 있었는데 마지막 한 발은 들리길 바랬던 거지.
He used a silencer, but he
wanted the last shot heard.
왜죠?
Why?
에바가 말했죠. 그 젊은 여경을 끌어들이기 위해
Eva said it. To draw
the young officer to him.
두 명의 경찰관을 죽일려고 왜 이 고생을 사서 했을까요?
Why go to all this trouble
to kill two officers
그 경찰관들이 커피를 마시는 동안에도 죽일 수 있었던 거잖아요?
he could have shot while
they were having their coffee?
그자는 쇼를 원했던거죠.
Because he wanted a show.
서장님. 자기가 그 저격자라고 하면서 스스로를 윈스턴 스미스라고 부르는데요.
Sir? He says he's the sniper.
He calls himself Winston Smith.
그자에요. 그 메모 "W.S.".
That's him. That's the note, "W.S."
죄송하지만 서장님. 그자는 특별히 다니엘 팀장님을 요청했습니다.
I'm sorry, sir, he asked
specifically for Major Daniel.
세바스찬. 전화 추적하게.
Sebastian, trace the call.
윈스턴 스미스?
Winston Smith?
선불폰으로 전화하고 있어서 추적은 못할거야.
I'm calling from a prepaid cell
phone that cannot be traced.
그럼 얼굴 보면서 이야기 해야겠군 그래. 만나지.
Then we should talk in person. Let's meet.
이게 웃기나?
Do you find this funny?
아니. 누가 살해당했는데 웃기겠나. 스미스. 아니야.
No. There is nothing funny
about murder, Mr. Smith. Nothing.
- 내 메모 가지고 있나?
- 그래.
- You have my note?
- Yes.
당신 태도를 추측해볼 수 있겠군. 돈은 물론 준비됐겠지?
Then I'm guessing by your
attitude you also have my money?
당신도 확실히 알고 있겠지만은 그만큼의 양의 돈을 모을려면 하루 이상 걸리지.
You surely know that we need
more than a day to raise that sum.
유럽 중앙 은행이
The European Central Bank
모든 EU 회원국들의 돈을 가지고 있지 않나?
holds money from every
country in the EU, does it not?
28개국에서 각각 삼백오십만 유로 이상씩 출자해놓잖아.
28 countries contributing just
over three and a half million each.
통계상의 약간의 변동만 해도 되잖아.
A statistical blip.
백만이면 약간의 변동이 아니지.
100 million is no blip.
그 폰 가지고 있어. 아침에 전화하지.
Keep that phone with you.
I'll call you in the morning.
나와 통화하길 요청했는데 우리 서로 아는 사인가?
You asked for me. Do we know each other?
모두가 당신을 알지.
Everybody knows you.
당신과 당신네 팀은 꽤 유명하지.
You and your team are quite famous.
하지만 그건 doublefast로 심지어는 증발하는거로 실패하게 될 수도 있지.
But that could be undone
doublefast, even vaporized.
도대체 무슨 말이야?
What the hell was that?
바로 소설 1984처럼 바로 그 신어같은거일거 같은데
I guess that's more Newspeak, like 1984.
돈은 28가지로 나누면 더 그럴듯하잖아.
The money is more plausible
if you split it in 28 ways.
28개국의 동의는 절대 못받을걸.
You'll never get 28 countries to agree.
유럽 의회 회기 본 적 있어?
Have you ever watched a session
of the European Parliament?
안자고 있었어요.
I'm not asleep.
근데 불도 안켜고 있었잖아.
But you are in the dark.
해가 지는 걸 보고 있었어요.
I watched the sun go down.
불을 켜야할 이유가 없었어요.
There was no reason to turn the light on.
해진지 두시간이 지났잖아.
Sun went down two hours ago.
빠리에 총격 사건 현장일은 어땠나요?
How did it go in Paris,
at the shooting scene?
일상적인 거지 뭐
Routine.
돈이 돈을 모을려고 전화 몇군데 돌리고 있어.
Dorn is making some calls
about getting the money.
집에서는 사건 이야기 금지
No cases at home.
좋은 아이디어네요
Good idea.
동의
Agreed.
근데... 뭐가 그렇게 괴롭히는데?
So... what is troubling you?
내가 해낼 수 있을지 모르겠어요. 루이.
I'm not sure I can do this, Louis.
모든게 나와 맞지 않은거 같아요. 그러니까...
Everything seemed foreign to me. So...
변한거지.
changed.
Okay.
이 일은 너무 중요해.
This work is too important.
못하겠으면
If you're not capable,
- 하면 안되겠지...
- 내가 못하겠다는 말은 아니에요.
- you should not do it...
- I didn't say I wasn't capable.
내 말은...
I mean...
뭘 기대하는거에요? 6년이라는 세월이 지난 후 첫날인데.
what do you expect, the
first day after six years?
그만두고 싶다고 말한 사람은 당신이야.
You are the one who said you want to quit.
살면서 난 절대 그만둔다는 말 한적 없어요.
I've never said quit in my life.
미안해.
I'm sorry.
내가 이 일을 못해낼거 같다고 생각하면
If you think I'm not capable of this job,
엄청 놀라게 될거에요. 다니엘씨.
you're going to be very
surprised, Mr. Daniel.
엄천 놀랄거에요.
Very surprised.
이번에 스타가 될거야.
You will be a star.
당신은 항상 스타야.
You always are.
Okay.
자 이제 잠자리로 가야겠군요.
Now, I'm ready for bed.
- 실제로는 피곤하지 않아.
- 내가 피곤하다고 그랬나요?
- I'm not really tired.
- Did I say tired?
내 입에서 피곤하다는 말이 나온적 있어요?
Did the word tired ever
come out of my mouth?
몇시지?
What time is it?
난...
I...
오 이런. 세상에. 간호사! 간호사!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Nurse! Nurse!
지금 몇시에요?
What time is it?
Shh... What? What, baby?
뭐? 뭐라고?
얼마나?
How long?
의사 불러 올게. 알았지.
Let me get the doctor, okay,
그러고나서 내가 다 설명해줄게.
and then I'll explain it all to you.
모든거 다. 알았지?
Everything, okay?
예.
Yes.
뭐?
What?
어디?
Where?
ICC에서 온 팀인가요?
Are you the team from the ICC?
- 루이 다니엘 팀장이에요.
- 맆첸 형삽니다.
- Major Louis Daniel.
- Detective Ripchen.
도와주신데 대해 감사드려요.
We appreciate the assistance.
- 이런 일이 발생한적 없어서...
- 도와주는게 아니에요.
- We've never had anything like this...
- We are not assisting.
같은 놈이 빠리에서 이틀 전 다섯명을 죽였습니다.
This same man killed five
people two days ago in Paris.
국경을 넘는 체계적으로 진행중인 범죄 건이죠.
This is a cross-border,
systematic, ongoing crime.
이 건은 공식적으로 우리 사건입니다. 당신 서장님은 통고받았을겁니다.
This is ours now, officially.
Your superiors have been notified.
- 아무도 얘기 안해줬는데요.
- 그럼 전화 해보세요.
- Well, no one told me.
- Then make the call,
그럼 내말이 맞았다는 걸 알게 되겠죠.
and when you learn I'm right,
시거 형사에게 어떠한 목격가 정보라도 다 넘기세요.
turn over any witness
information to Detective Seeger.
- 전화 좀 몇군데 돌리고요.
- 그러세요.
- Let me make some calls.
- Yeah.
상당히 솔직하게 밀어붙이시네요.
Well, that was pretty straightforward.
해야 일이 있잖아. 어서 하세.
We have work to do, so let's do it.
여기요. 맥코널이구요. 버거, 시거, 빝토리아. ICC에서 왔어요.
Hey, mate. McConnell, Berger,
Seeger and Vittoria from the ICC.
예. 그쪽에서 온다고 들었어요.
Yes, we heard you were coming.
모든 시신은 쓰러진 곳에 아직도 그대로 있나요?
All the bodies are still in
the spots where they fell?
모두 다섯 구에요.
All five.
의료진이 검시하지 않았나요?
Medics didn't work on them?
모두 머리를 관통당했어요. 검사는 이뤄지지 않았구요.
They were all shot through the
head. There was nothing to work on.
어디서 발사된건가요?
Where did the shots come from?
모르겠어요.
We don't know.
아무도 방향을 알려줄 총성 한 방도 듣지 못했어요.
No one heard a single shot to
give us a direction to look.
소음기를 사용했군.
He used suppressors.
옥상에 대한 수색이 있었는데요.
There were some searches of the rooftops,
어둠속이라 아무런 증거도 발견되지 않았어요.
but no evidence was found in the dark.
금일 아침에 다른 수색이 있을 예정이죠.
There will be another search this morning.
스캔젠으로 총알 경로, 희생자들을 관통한 탄도를
I might be able to use the
ScanGen to establish a bullet path,
규명할 수 있을지 모르겠군.
a trajectory through the victims.
두 세구 정도 하면 3각 측량을 할 수 있겠어.
If we can do that with two
or three, we can triangulate.
근데 총을 맞기 전에 있던
But you'll need to know the exact position
정확한 위치를 알아야 하잖아.
they were in before they were shot, though.
그렇지. 희생자들이 앉아있었는 서 있었는지
Yeah, whether they were
sitting or standing.
가족들은 여기 있나요?
Did the family members stay?
예. 모스크에 있어요.
Yes. They are in the mosque.
이맘(성직자)과 그의 부인이 그 사람들을 보살피고 있어요.
The Imam and his wife
are taking care of them.
그 사람들이 앉아있었는지 아니면 서 있었는지를 기억하고 있는지 알아볼 수 있겠군.
We can see if they remember whether
they were sitting or standing.
우리가 스캔하는 동안에
While we scan the bodies.
팜케?
Famke?
주전자 좀 불에 올려 놓아줘요.
Can you put the kettle on?
저장소에서 오래된 책들을 좀 찾았죠.
I found some old books in storage.
이 주변에서 더 이상 법률 책을 읽는 사람이 없나봐요?
Doesn't anyone read the
law around here anymore?
그쪽은... ?
You are... ?
레베가 다니엘? 어제 만났었죠?
Rebecca Daniel? We met yesterday?
그러니까 누구신지는 아는데요. 이곳에 있다는게
Well, I know who you are, but you're here,
- 그리고 아직 아침 7시밖에 안됐는데요.
- 걱정 말아요.
- and it's only 7:00 a.m.
- Don't worry.
그쪽에 이렇게 이른 시간에 오라고 바라지 않아요.
I don't expect you to be here this early.
아니. 아니요. 전 좋아요. 지금까지 누구도...
No, no, I love it. No one ever...
이 책들은 갖다 놓을게요.
Let me put those books away.
팜케...
Famke...
지금 당장 블랙 커피 한 잔 하고 싶은데요.
right now I would love
a cup of black coffee.
알았어요.
Okay.
그리고... 프랑스 빠리와 불가리아 소피아에서
Then... I want legal
precedent on multiple homicide
발생한 다중 살인과 총기와 폭행 관련
and all lesser included
gun and battery charges,
모든 경범죄에 대한 법적 판례가 필요해요.
in Paris, France and Sofia, Bulgaria.
ICC 팀에서 이 저격범을 잡았을 때 적절하게 기소할 준비를 하고 싶어요.
I want to be ready to charge this
sniper properly when they catch him.
책들은 나중도 해도 되구요.
The books can wait.
ICC 팀에서 그자를 잡으면 이라는 거 맞죠?
You mean if they catch him, right?
팜케. 우리 남편을 잘 몰라서 그러는거에요.
Oh, Famke, you clearly
don't know my husband.
어서 이 개새끼!
Come on, you son of a bitch!
웃기군. 당신은 주로 내 얼굴에 대고 바른 말만 하잖아요.
Funny, you usually say
that right to my face.
당신이 욕하는 걸 나한테 들킬지 몰랐는데요..
I don't think I've ever
caught you calling me names.
폰은 지니고 있어. 아침에 전화하지.
"Keep that phone with you. I
will call you in the morning."
- 그게 그자가 나한테 한 말이지.
- 나도 거기 있었어요.
- That's what he said to me.
- I was there.
- 그자는 거짓말했어.
- 그랬나? 아직 아침이지만요.
- He lied.
- Did he? It's still morning.
그자는 다섯명 이상의 사람들을 죽였네.
He killed five more people.
메모에 그럴거라고 했잖아요.
He said he was going
to do that in the note.
'목요일에 다섯명 이상' 내가 말할 수 있는 건,
"Five more on Thursday".
As far as I can tell,
이 모든 일이 바로 한밤 중에 발생했단거죠.
this whole thing happened
right about midnight.
그자는 목요일까지 기다렸어요.
He waited until Thursday.
그자는 나에게 돈 모을 기회조차 주지 않았어.
He didn't even give me a
chance to get the money.
'나에게'요?
"Me?"
'우리에게'죠.
Us.
그자는 우리에게 기회를 주지 않았어요.
He didn't give us a chance,
단언컨데 그점이 논쟁거리가 되겠네요.
and I'm sure that he
would argue that point.
그자는 "목요일에"라 했고
He said "on Thursday."
그 날이 지나갔고 우리는 이게 정말
That has passed, but you don't really think
돈 문제라고는 생각하지 않았었는데요?
this is about the money, do you?
뭐에 관한 걸까?
What is it about?
그걸 아직 우리가 모르는거죠.
That we don't know yet.
아자씨들! 뭔가 찾은거 같은데요.
Hey, lads! We might have something.
아직까지는
Not yet.
그러니까 제가 시신을 스캔하고
So, I was able to scan the bodies
시신들을 관통한 총알들의 궤적을 규명했죠.
and establish the path of the
bullets as they passed through them.
아라벨라. 불 좀 꺼줘.
Arabela, can you turn
off the lights, please?
자 이게 총알 궤적들입니다.
Okay, these lines are bullet trajectories.
그러니까 아라벨라와 제가 총을 맞기전 희생자들의 위치에 대해
Well, Arabela and I were able to
talk to the companions of the victims
희생자 일행들과 이야기를 나눴죠.
about their position before they were shot.
대부분의 희생자들이 매우 구체적이었어요.
Most of them were very specific.
예를 들자면 한 희생자는 담요를 덥고 다리를 꼰 상태로
For instance, victim one
was sitting cross-legged
앉아서 영화를 보고 있었어요.
on a blanket watching the movie,
두 번째 희생자는 그의 약혼자가 희생자 등을 기댄채 앉아 있었고요.
victim two was sitting up with his
fianc?leaning back against him,
세 번째 희생자는 화장실에 갔다가 통로로 오고 있었죠.
and victim three was walking through
the aisles coming back from the loo.
자 이게 그 정보를 추가해서 모델링 해보면...
Now, when I add that
information to the modelling...
저기가 가장 높은 지점이에요.
That's the highest point.
이 지점이라면 확실히 광장 전체를 커버하죠.
Well, this point definitely
covers the entire square.
스캔젠 가져와서 어느 잔여물이라도 찾을 수 잇는지 알아봐야겠네요.
I'll go get the ScanGen and
see if we can find any residue,
이곳이 맞는지 확인해봐야죠.
make sure this is the right spot.
그런 수고 안해도 되겠는데
Hey, don't bother.
- "단 한 사람의 소수."
- 무슨 의미의 말이야?
- "Minority of one."
- Mean something to you?
책에서 참조한 다른 문구야.
It's another reference to the book.
주인공 캐릭터가 물어보지 '미친 사람이 되는건
The lead character asks if being a lunatic
바로 단 한 사람의 소수가 되는것이냐'고.
is just being a minority of one.
내가 책 읽는걸 싫어한다고 해서 잘 모른다는 말은 아니야.
Just because I don't like to read
doesn't mean I'm not good at it.
이봐들
Guys.
즐기고 있나?
Enjoying yourself?
살인 관련해서 어떻게 즐길 수 있겠나. 다니엘씨.
There is nothing enjoyable
about murder, Mr. Daniel.
없지.
Nothing.
돈에 관심없군.
You're not interested in money.
그 돈을 조금이라도 쓰기 전에 오래전에 죽어 나자빠졌겠지.
I'll be dead long before
I can spend any of it.
원하는게 뭐야?
What do you want?
프랑스인이었지 않나?
You used to be French, right?
아직도 프랑스인이야.
I am still French.
아니. 지금은 유럽인이지.
No. You're European now.
유럽 연합의 시민이지. 우리는 우리의 정체성을 포기해버렸지. 루이.
A citizen of the European Union.
We gave up our identities, Louis.
우리는 정부 관료들이 좀 더
We let a bunch of bureaucrats
수월한 무역을 할려고 수세기 동안 수립된 개성을 내다 버리게 그냥 뒀지.
throw away centuries of
individuality for easier trade.
돈때문에.
For money.
더욱이 당신 팀은 혐오스러워.
Even your team is an abomination.
불가리아 소피아시에 있는 지붕에서 뭘하고 있나?
What are you doing on a
rooftop in Sofia, Bulgaria?
그런식으로 일을 처리하더군. 공동으로 처리하는 식.
That's how it works. How
the collective takes over.
우선 그들이 당신 돈을 바꾸게 되면 당신은 불안정한 경제 기반이 불안정하게 되지.
First they change your money so
you're on shaky economic ground,
그러면 그들이 지방 자치 정부의 익숙한 형태로 인수받게되지.
then they take over the familiar
forms of local government,
경찰과 같은.
like the police.
당신이 아는 모든건
Everything you know
변하게 되겠지.
changes
당신이 윈스턴 스미스같은 바퀴의 톱니처럼 될때까지
until you're just like a cog
in the wheel like Winston Smith.
정부 직원으로서 말이지.
A functionary.
루이. 정말로?
Oh, Louis. Really?
당신 밑에 있지 않았나?
Isn't that beneath you?
원하는게 뭔가?
What is it you want?
내 메시지를 알리고 싶다.
I want my message out.
내가 꼭 해야만 할 말들을 사람들이 들었으면 하고 그 일을 딩신이 했으면 하는거지.
I want people to hear what I have
to say, and I want you to do it,
당신과 당신 팀 놈들이 말이야.
you and your team of bastard cops.
내가 당신 메시지를 전달해주길 바란다고?
You want me to deliver your message?
세계에서 온 카메라들 앞에서 기자 회견을 해줘야겠는데.
Mm-hmm, at a press conference
before the world's cameras.
만약에 하지 않겠다면?
And if I don't?
내일 5섯 말을 쏘겠지.
I have five rounds for tomorrow,
그리고 그 다음 날도 또 그 다음날도
and the day after that,
and the day after that.
답을 줄려고 연락할려면 어떻게 해야 되지?
How will I contact you
to give you an answer?
기자 회견이 답이 될거야.
The press conference will be the answer.
아니면 답이 아니고.
Or not.
내가 메시지를 받겠지.
I'll get the message.
아라벨라. 우리가 성명을 발표할거라고 언론에 알려줘.
Arabela, tell the press
we'll make an announcement.
알겠습니다.
Yes, sir.
잠깐 기달려. 그러니까...
Wait, wait, there's...
언론한테서 필요한 뭔가 더 있어.
there's something else
that we need from them.
헬기 영상이 생방으로 나가는 곳이
We need to know where on the continent
유럽 대륙 어디인지 알아야겠네.
that chopper's images
are broadcasting live.
생방으로 나가는데
Absolutely live.
그자가 날 봤어. 내가 손가락을 치켜 든걸 그자가 봤어.
He saw me. He saw me raise the finger.
그러니까요. 대부분 네트워크 방송들은 뉴스 속보할 때 30초 딜레이를 주지.
Yeah. Well, most networks add a 30
second time delay for breaking news,
너무 충격적인 사건이 발생할 때를 대비해서 말이야.
in case something too shocking happens.
방송을 내보내기에 너무 충격적인지를 고려하는 방송국이 어딘지를 알아봐야겠군요.
I'd like to find out what the network
considers too shocking to show.
리스트는 하루가 달리 점점 작아지겠군요 그럼.
The list gets smaller every day.
좋아. 들어봐.
All right, listen up.
언론은 경찰이 떼거지로 나와 이야기 하는 걸 좋아하지 않아.
The press doesn't like to
talk to the police in groups.
언론은 괴롭힘을 당하고 있다는 걸 보이고 싶어하지 않거든.
They don't want to look
like they're being bullied.
하지만 따로 따로라면 그 언론들 모두 친구처럼 지내고 싶어할거야.
But separately, they all want to
make out like they're your friend
그럼 그 언론에서 기사를 쓸려고 나중에 자네들한테 요청하겠지.
so they can call on you later for a story.
언론은 믿는 경찰. 그건 바보죠.
Any cop who trusts the press is an idiot.
언론에 자네들이 협조적이라고 생각하게끔 만들어줘.
Let them think you will cooperate.
자네들이 친구들이라고 생각하게 해주란 말이지.
Let them think you're friends.
그래. 명함을 주고 핸드폰 번호로 알려주고
That's right. Hand out cards,
give them your cell number.
이 친구 번호 알려줘도 되나요?
Can I give them his cell number?
어 그래 그럼 난 니 번호 알려줄게.
Aye, and I'll give them yours.
- 누가 너한테 내 번호 알려줬는데?
- 몰라도 돼.
- Who gave you my cell number?
- You don't want to know.
루이. 이 영상이 생방으로 나가는데가 어딘지 알아내면
Louis, finding where those
images are broadcasting live
우리가 조사할 지역이 나오겠죠.
will give us an area to look in,
하지만 범위를 좁히는 방법을 찾아야겠어요.
but we need to find a
way to narrow that down.
- 무슨 아이디어 있나?
- 있죠.
- You have an idea?
- Yeah.
내 생각에 그나 누구인가에 근거해서요.
Based on who I think he is.
- 자네 생각에?
- 상당히 확신하고 있어요.
- You think?
- I'm pretty sure.
만약에 틀리면?
And if you're wrong?
사람들이 죽어 나가겠죠.
People may die.
지금도 사람들이 죽어 나가고 있네.
People are dying now.
뭐 알아낸거 있나?
What do you got?
헬기 영상이 생방으로 나가는데는 네 군데 밖에 없어요.
Only four sources broadcast
from that particular chopper live
딜레이가 전혀 없이
without any delay whatsoever.
스페인, 포르투갈 서해쪽을 커버하고 있는 방송국
A station covering west
coast of Spain and Portugal.
그리고 노르웨이 전역
And all of Norway.
오스트리아 절반하고 스위스 전역
Half of Austria, and all of Switzerland.
소피아는? 지역 방송하는데가 없어?
Not Sofia? Not locally?
이 지역은 방송하는데가 전혀 없어요.
They weren't broadcasting anything at all.
너무 가까운거죠. 시신이 아직도 현장 바닥에 있는데
It's too close for them. The
bodies are still on the ground.
스페인하고 포르투갈은 그자가 뭘 하기에는 너무 멀고요.
Spain and Portugal are too far
for what he's capable of doing.
빠리, 고향, 지금 소피아 그러면 확실하군 다시 고향이겠군.
Paris, home, now Sofia,
and, apparently, home again.
노르웨이도 너무 먼 거 같고
Norway seems too far as well.
그래요. 최선의 선택지는 오스트리아 아니면 스위스군.
It is. Our best shot is
Austria or Switzerland.
자네들은 헬기가 있는 곳으로 가줘야겠네.
You guys should head in that
direction on the chopper.
그리고는요?
And do what, man?
오스트리아하고 스위는는 수색하기엔 상당히 넓은데요.
Austria and Switzerland is
a pretty big search area.
나한테 맡겨주게.
Leave that to me.
무슨 말인가요?
What do you mean?
내가 이번 기자 회견을 통해서 범위를 좁혀볼 생각이야.
I'm going to do this press conference
and I'm going to narrow it down.
그자가 말하길 루이 팀장님이 기자 회견을 해주길 원하지 않았었나요?
Didn't he say he wanted Louis
to do the press conference?
누가 기자 회견을 하는가는 적어도 그자 문제겠지.
Who is doing the talking will
be the least of his problems.
특히 내가 말하는걸 들었을 땐 말이지.
Especially when he
hears what I have to say.
하지만 그렇게 되면 좀 더 많은 희생자를 만드는 위험이 있지 않나요?
But won't that put more victims at risk?
이게 먹히지 않는다면 그렇겠지.
Only if it doesn't work.
스나이퍼 집을 급습하는데 난 자네들이 원하는 그런 사람이 아니지 않나?
I'm not the guy you want on a raid
of a sniper's house anyway, am I?
그리고 이 윈스턴이라는 자를 직접 만나보고 싶기도 하고.
And I want to meet this
Mr. Winston in person.
세바스찬 자네는 여기 남아줘야 겠네. 그리고 우리에게
Sebastian, you should
stay and we can check out
들어오는 정보를 확인할 수가 있지.
any information that comes in.
위성 전화로 통화하세.
We will be on the sat phone.
- 잘되길 바랄게요.
- 고맙네.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
제 이름은 칼 히크먼입니다. 뉴욕 형사를 은퇴하고
My name is Carl Hickman. I'm a
retired New York City detective
현재 헤이그에 있는 ICC 수사팀에서 일하고 있습니다.
who now works for the ICC's
investigative team out of The Hague.
우리는 현재 소피아에서 며칠 전 빠리에서 총격으로 발생한 다수의
We are currently assisting
the Sofia, Bulgaria police
사망자 사건을 일으킨 자와 동일한 자가 일으킨
in investigating this
latest cowardly attack
비열한 사건을 수사중인 불가리아 경찰을
by the same man who shot
a number of people in Paris
도와주고 있습니다.
a couple of days ago.
우리는 실제로
We have actually been in
통화를 했습니다. 이 개새...
contact with this piece of sh...
이 가해자와
with this perpetrator,
그자는 우리에게 기자 회견을 열라고 요청을 하였죠.
and he asked us to have
this press conference...
비열한거 맞아.
Cowardly's right.
옥상에서 사람들을 쏘는건
Shooting people from the roof of something,
심지어 희생자들은 자기들이 타겟이라는것도 모르잖아.
they don't even know they are targets.
일종의 사냥이라도 말이지.
Kind of like hunting though.
사냥같은게 아니지.
It's nothing like hunting...
주장하는게...
... could make a point is by murdering
10명의 무고한 사람들이 살해함으로써 요구하는게...
10 innocent people and demanding...
- 한잔 더.
- 아 정말로. 그냥 말로하면 안되요?
- Another.
- Mein gott. How about just asking?
하지만 그자가 원하는걸 신경쓰지 않습니다.
... but never mind what he wants.
대신에 우리가 할 말은 이렇습니다.
Here's what we're going
to talk about instead.
여러분들께 말씀드리죠. 그자를 잡는데 어떻게 도와주실지 말입니다.
I'm going to tell you how
you can help us catch him.
경찰이 연쇄 살인범은 잡은 후에 어떻습니까?
You know how after police
catch a serial killer,
이웃 주민들은 항상 그러죠 '그 사람이 그럴 줄 전혀 몰랐다'고요.
the neighbors always say
that they had no idea?
'그 사람은 정말 조용한 사람이이었다고, 절대 남을 괴롭힌적이 없다고'들 하시죠.
"He was such a quiet guy,
he never bothered anybody."
그치만 이자는 그런 사람이 아닙니다.
Well, that's not this guy.
가해자가 되기 위한 조건을 가진 성격을 가지고 있지도 않습니다.
That's not the make-up of a
personal cause perpetrator.
이자는 조용하지 않습니다. 이자는 모든 사람들을 괴롭히고 있습니다.
This guy's not quiet.
This guy bothers everybody.
여러분들은 그자를 알고 있습니다. 하지만 여러분들의 친구들 중에 있지도 않습니다.
You know him, but you're not friends.
그자는 실은 자기가 받아줄만한 사람도 많지 않습니다.
In fact, he doesn't have
many people that he tolerates
그리고 친구도 없죠. 못된놈이라서요.
and he has no friends because he's a jerk.
그리고 불평하죠. 큰소리로
And he complains. Loudly.
그자는 유럽연합의 형성에 대해 반복적으로 불평을 할겁니다.
He will have complained repeatedly
about the formation of the EU,
새로운 시스템 아래에 개인 정체성의 상실에 대해서도 불평할겁니다.
and about the loss of individual
identity under the new system.
그리고는 이렇게 말할 수도 있겠군요.
And he might have said,
다른 시간대에 이 말과 매우 유사한 말투로
at different times, something
very similar to these words,
우리는 정부 관료들이 좀 더
"We let a bunch of bureaucrats
수월한 무역을 할려고 수세기 동안 수립된 개성을
toss out a century worth of individuality
내다 버리게 그냥 뒀지.
just to make trade easier.
돈때문에
For money."
아니면 이런식으로...
Or something like...
공동으로 처리하는 식으로
"The collective takes over.
있잖아요. 우선 여러분들의 돈을 바꾸고
You know, first they change your money,
경찰을 바꾸고 그러고 나면 정부를 바꾸는 거죠.
then they change the police, and
then they change the government
그리고는 그들이 여러분들을 아무것도 아닌듯 짓밟아 버리겠죠.
and they crush you like you're nothing,
여러분들은 바퀴의 톱니에 불과합니다.
and you're just a cog in the wheel."
이런 자입니다.
That's this guy.
그러니 그자를 잡을 수 있게 도와주십시오.
So help us catch him,
아래 자막으로 나오는 번호로 전화 주십시오.
and call the number that's flashing
on the bottom of the screen.
어딘선가 들어본거 같으시다면 전화주십시오.
If this guy sounds familiar, call us.
고맙습니다.
Thank you.
히크먼입니다.
Hickman.
확실한가?
Are you sure?
묘사하는게 그자와 완벽하게 일치합니다.
The description fits him perfectly.
더해서 전화 준 사람이 말하길 그자는 1984 책에 집착한다네요.
Plus, the caller said this
guy's obsessed with 1984,
그리고 이건 공개된 정보가 아니에요.
and that was not public info.
그자의 진짜 이름을 말해주던가?
Did they tell you his real name?
알렉산더 퍼스터. 오스트리아 국적.
Alexander Fuster, Austrian National.
여기 알렉산더 퍼스터에 대한 뉴스 기사가 있어요.
There are some newspaper
articles about an Alexander Fuster
프랑스 외인 부대에서 싸웠던 사람이네요.
who fought for the French Foreign Legion
SWAT 팀으로 옮겼구요.
and then headed a SWAT team.
유러폴에서 근무 중 총격건으로 그를 기소에 회부했군요.
Europol referred him for prosecution
after an on-duty shooting.
기소?
Prosecution?
기사에 따르면
According to the reports,
신참 경찰이 인질을 나쁜놈으로 오인했고
a rookie cop misidentified
a hostage as the bad guy,
퍼스터는 사격 허가를 받기 전에 그사람을 죽였어요.
and Fuster killed him before
he had any authorization.
아마도 그것때문에 빠리에서 신참 여경과의 따로 시간을 만들었겠군요.
Maybe that's why he took his
time with the rookie in Paris.
- 경과 내용을 알려주겠네.
- 그래요.
- I'll let you know what happens.
- All right.
오스트리아 클라겐푸르트 외곽
Austria, outside Klagenfurt,
남쪽 국경지대
the south border.
시간이 됐군.
It's time.
오두막은 500m이내에 있어요.
The cabin is about a half kilometer in.
지금 경계를 대충 세웠어요.
We have a soft perimeter right now.
부하들에게 엄폐물을 찾으라고 하세요.
Tell your men to find cover.
그자는 무시무시하게 정확한 원거리 사격 실력을 가지고 있어요.
He's a fierce accurate long-range shot.
알랙산더. 나와!
Alexander, come out!
괜찮으세요?
Are you okay, sir?
당신은 완전히 포위되었다!
You are completely surrounded!
괜히 나쁘게...
Don't make this...
타미. 얼마나 잘하는거 같아?
Tommy, how good is he?
내가 본것 중에 최고 중에 한 사람이에요. 왜요?
One of the best I've ever seen. Why?
두 번다 날 맟줄 수도 있었던거잖아.
He could have shot me both times.
높게 쐈어.
He shot high.
그치만 확실한건 아니잖아요.
Well, you don't know that for sure.
팀장님. 제 생각엔...
Major, I don't think that's...
알랙산더!
Alexander!
지금 나간다!
I am coming out of cover!
무장없이! 이야기 좀 하지!
Unarmed! Let's talk!
쏠 때 알려주게.
Let me know when you have a shot.
예. 팀장님.
Yes, Major.
우선 대화없이 날 쏠려고
You didn't bring me here
이곳으로 불러오지 않았겠지.
to shoot me without talking first.
나한테 할말이 있잖아.
You have something to say to me.
나오게.
Come out.
알랙산더
Alexander.
당신같은 오지랖쟁이들이 내 인생을 망쳐놓는단 말이야.
Busybodies like you ruined my life.
방아쇠를 당긴 건 내가 아니잖아.
I didn't pull that trigger.
그 인질을 다치게 할 의도는 없었지.
I had no intention of hurting that hostage,
유로폴도 알고 있었고 말이야.
and Europol knew it.
그리고 그 유로폴들은 오스트리아에서 그런 권한도 없었어.
And they had no authority to be in Austria,
하물며 나와 내 부하들에게 뭘 할 수 있다고 말하는 것은 어불성설이지.
much less telling me and
my men what I could do.
유로폴
Europol,
인터폴
Interpol,
그리고 지금 당신의 ICC도
and now your ICC.
지역 경찰들이 하게 나둬. 할 수 있겠어?
Leave the local police
alone, can you do that?
세상은 점점 작아지고 있지.
The world is getting smaller.
날마다 조금씩
Every day, a bit smaller.
그리고는 사람들을 삼켜버리지.
And swallowing people.
삶도 삼켜버리고 개성도 삼켜버리지.
Swallowing lives, swallowing individuality.
나 내 정체성을 잃지 않았어.
I am not losing my identity,
자라고 있지.
it's growing.
난 시민이야.
I am a citizen,
그냥 프랑스인이 아니고
not just of France,
유럽 시민이지, 세계 시민이지.
but a citizen of Europe, of the world.
사람들이 이탈리아 경사와 아일랜드 경찰이
When people realize that Italian sergeants
그들 주권국의 시민들을 괴롭히고 사법권없이
and Irish cops are bullying
their sovereign citizens
사람들을 죽인다는 걸 알아챌 때 반항하게 되겠지.
and killing people they have no
jurisdiction over, they will rebel.
그 누군도 다른 누군가에 의해 죽임을 당하면 안되지.
No one has to be killed by anyone.
사정권에 들어왔어요.
I have a shot.
저두요.
Me, too.
나한테 두명읠 스나이퍼가 있어.
I have two snipers of my own,
그리고 지금 당장 둘 사 사격이 가능하지.
and right now, they both have shots.
잘해?
Are they good?
엄청.
Very.
당신 스나이퍼들이 날 앞에 두고도 못쏘는 이유는
Because if they can't get
a shot off before I do,
그건 당신을 위해 사격을 안하는 거지.
then it's lights out for you.
- 우리 둘 다를 위해서지.
- 하지만 다른 점은
- For both of us.
- But the difference is,
난 죽을 준비가 돼있어.
I am prepared to die.
유럽에 메이저 신문사들에게 성명서을 보냈어.
I've mailed manifestos to all
the major papers of Europe.
뉴스 방송사들에게 비디오 테이프도 돌렸고
I've taped videos for the news networks.
당신이 하고픈 메시지를 듣게끔 할려고 죽을 필요는 없어.
You don't have to die for
your message to be heard.
당신의 작아진 세계는 비주얼적인거지.
Your smaller world is a visual one.
오늘날 당신이 뭘 주장할려면 죽어야만 하지.
Today, you pretty much do
have to die to make your point.
당신은 주장한거야...
You made your point...
쓸데없는데
for nothing.
미켈. 테러리스트 사건으로 갈거에요.
Michel, we're going to
go with terrorism as well.
레베카...
Rebecca...
그자를 기소하지 않을거네.
we will not be prosecuting the sniper.
뭐라고요?
I'm sorry?
ICC 팀이 그자를 죽였어.
The team, he made them kill him.
루이는 괜찮나요?
Is Louis all right?
괜찮아. 팀이 오는 중이야.
Oh, fine. They're on the way back home.
잘됐네요.
Good.
고마워. 레베카.
Thank you, Rebecca.
- Hey.
- 팀원들은 집에 다들 갔나?
- 예. 예. 방금 전 다들 떠났어요.
- Did the team go home?
- Yeah, yeah, everybody just left.
혹시...
Did, um...
앤-마리 어머니가 오늘 들러서... 그러니까 그녀 물건을 가져 갔나요?
Anne-Marie's mom, did she come
by today and... and get her stuff?
- 아니.
- 오.
- No.
- Oh.
전화하셨네.
She called.
암스테르담까지 다 오셔서는
She came all the way to Amsterdam and then
사무실을 볼 수 없겠다고 하시더군.
she couldn't face the office.
여기 오면 진짜가 되고 마지막이 될거 같아서
She said coming here made
it too real, too final.
쉐리... 있잖아요. 야시장에 있는 친구요.
Shari, my... my friend from the carnival,
그녀... 그녀가 어제 깨어났어요.
she... she woke up last night.
그랬어? 왜 말 안했나?
Oh, she did? Why didn't you tell me?
그냥, 오늘 적당한 시간을 찾지 못해서요.
Ah, just, uh, didn't find the time today.
그녀는 어떤가?
How is she?
의사 말로는 그녀 상태가 더 좋다는데요...
The doctors say that she's better than...
자기들이... 기대한것보다
than they'd... than they'd hoped.
근데...?
But... ?
얼마나 오랫동안 의식을 잃고 잇었는지 알고 싶어해서요.
She wants to know how
long she was unconscious.
내 생각엔 그녀가 진짜 알고 싶은건 무슨 일이 생겼나인거 같아요.
I think she really wants
to know what happened.
그럴만한 질문이군.
Fair question.
그렇죠. 내가 꺼리는 대답이죠.
Yeah. It's the answer that I don't like.
대답이 뭔가?
What's the answer?
내 주변에 있는 사람들에게 폭력이 발생하죠. 루이. 좋은 사람들에게
Rough stuff happens to people
around me, Louis, good people.
난 아프다고 울지 않았네.
I'm not crying about it.
사실이에요.
It's just true.
수년동안 자네를 알고 지내왔지만
I have known you for years.
나쁜일이 생기지 않았네.
Nothing bad's happened to me.
내가 '좋은 사람들에게'라고 했잖아요.
I said "good people."
정신적 지원 차원에서 같이 가줄까?
Want me to come with you,
to be your moral support?
됐어요.
No.
어떨 때는 혼자서 걸어 나가야 하기도 하잖아요?
Some walks you've got to
do on your own, you know?
그래. 알고 있네.
Yes. I do know.
고마워요.
Thank you.
모두가 다 볼 수 있게 해야죠.
Should be for everyone to see.